Miss Danielle Kriel has come to The SCOAN from South Africa with the terrible problem of bipolar disorder.
At just 16 years old she has been tormented by this terrible problem for several years,
having to live in isolation and to be consistently watched due to her obsession with cutting her veins,
just to see blood.
The medical report clearly states the symptoms that have plagued Danielle's life,
as a result of the bipolar disorder; depression, suicidal thoughts, and self-harm.
The disturbing photographs by her side show Danielle's self-inflicted wounds in an attempt to commit suicide.
We can also see a "missing child" notice, showing how the bipolar disorder
had even caused this young teenager to run away from home.
There are demonic forces that cause people to be bowed down in bondage.
Now, in the arena of liberty, the demonic forces behind the bondage of this young girl are about to be exposed
and disconnected, in Jesus' name.
Let's listen to her.
My name is Danielle Kriel; I’m 16 years old, and I’m from South Africa.
Who is the person sitting next to you?
It’s my mum.
The problem that brought me to The SCOAN is mental disorder – bipolar disorder,
borderline personality disorder, obsessive-compulsive disorder (OCD) and chronic depression.
I also have the problem of self-harm and suicidal tendencies.
For how many years have you had all these problems?
For nine years.
I can’t go to school.
I do home-schooling.
I also have panic attacks.
I can’t wear short sleeves because I have to hide the cuts and scars.
I would have anxiety and rage attacks in school.
So, that made it impossible for me to go to school and I had to have home-schooling.
Normally, I would just rush out of the classroom, go to the bathroom
and there, I would either cut myself or punch the walls or I would bite – anything to inflict pain.
It was always on yourself, not towards others?
No - it was always on myself but I felt the urge to do it to others; that is why I isolate myself -
not to do it on others.
Can you show us your arms and the scars you are talking about?
These are all the scars.
Some of them have faded.
There are a few like this one where I almost died – it was near fatal – these two.
It is only by the grace of God that I am still alive.
The multiple scars that criss-cross her arms tell their own story of pain and agony,
as the addiction to cutting herself and seeing blood has almost taken her life.
What is it that makes you start cutting and harming yourself?
Most of the time, it’s when emotionally, I am too overwhelmed and I can’t cope.
Then, I would get into a rage.
Also, when I feel the urge to hurt others, I will do it to myself instead before I would calm down
so that I would not hurt others.
It is satisfying to see the blood and even sometimes, I get the urge to drink the blood.
It is also satisfying and numbs every emotion.
It cuts everything off – I become like a total zombie and don’t have to face reality.
The first time, it lasted a long time and then, as I cut more and more, it lasted a shorter time
and I had to cut deeper to get the same effect.
So, when you were cutting yourself - how do you normally go about that?
Sometimes, I would do it on impulse.
I would just grab something and randomly slice wherever I can.
I used razor blades, glass and the blades of sharpeners.
Sometimes, it’s on impulse – I just grab something and do it;
at other times, I plan it for a long time and then do it.
Anytime this rage comes upon you and you don't have the opportunity to cut yourself,
how does this affect you; what else do you do?
Then, I start biting, scratching and eating walls.
Normally, when there is someone there, I will isolate myself and then do it
because I know I can’t make any noise.
I would just use anything I could find and if that was not enough, I would break a mirror.
I would use anything sharp I could find to cut and inflict pain.
Have you tried to stop these kind of things by yourself?
I can’t stop; it has gotten worse and worse.
I have to do it; I can’t stop.
You mentioned that you have had suicidal thoughts and tendencies.
Tell us - what were some of the close encounters you have had.
There has been quite a few.
The latest one was that I drank poison.
The one before that, I am not sure; it was amitraz – something to kill fleas and dogs.
I found it in the cupboard.
I prepared everything and wrote notes and took everything.
Just a while before that, I cut and I cut too deep.
I hit the artery and bled almost completely out.
The doctor said I had 30 millilitres of blood left in me.
So, it was only by the grace of God that He kept me alive, that I didn’t die in that incident.
Also, on numerous times, I have overdosed on pills – any pills I could find.
I have tried hanging myself and every time, it just failed.
It either has no effect on me or someone just comes and interrupts and stops it.
Every time, something just stops it.
Now, you are here at The SCOAN, what do you believe God Almighty will do for you?
I believe He will deliver me and set me free completely and then
I will have a relationship with Him and be able to help others in the same situation as me
who isn’t understood and I can help them through the grace of God.
Amen.
We believe with you that God Almighty will heal you completely and set you free, in the name of Jesus Christ.
Let's hear a word from your mother.
I am Mrs Kriel, from South Africa and I am the mother of Danielle.
I must watch her 24/7, 365.
It is quite a job – to be a watcher, to hear any sounds,
all the knives and every sharp item, there is nothing there -
even stuff to clean the house, I lock it away.
My weapons, I lock them away in the safe.
My marriage – I nearly divorced my husband because it has an influence on our family life.
I myself have rage and I can’t take it anymore.
A friend suggested that we must come to The SCOAN and get deliverance from God.
How did you first discover this problem in the life of your daughter?
At the age of 12, the teacher phoned me.
She was doing home-schooling in a centrum and the teacher phoned me
that I should quickly come to the office.
I drove to her office and then she informed me that Danielle had cut herself.
From there on, I was watching her.
She would go from friend to friend watching Danielle
because I was the sole breadwinner at that stage.
After work, I would pick her up.
At one stage, she was staying with friends on a farm for 10 months and they would look after Danielle.
We took her to the institution, Denmar in South Africa but it was not successful
and the doctors stated that she was supposed to be in an institute for the rest of her life.
Now, you are here at The SCOAN, what do you believe God Almighty will do for your daughter?
He will deliver her completely.
Amen. We believe with you that God Almighty will deliver both you and your daughter,
in the name of Jesus Christ.
Amen.
DELIVERANCE TIME
Man of God, deliver me!
I’ve been struggling with self-harm and suicide.
Please, Man of God, have mercy on me!
I cut myself.
I have been doing this since 12.
Please, Man of God, deliver me!
We can't take it anymore.
Please, God!
It’s spiritual attacks – evil spirits.
Stuff which happened to her as a child – she never told me.
Many times – more than 20, 30 – she is cutting her veins.
Man of God, please, help me!
Prophet T.B. Joshua Ministering Prayer & Deliverance in Jesus’ Name
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Manifestation Of Evil Spirits
Prophet T.B. Joshua Ministering Prayer & Deliverance in Jesus’ Name
TESTIMONY TIME
Emmanuel!
(God With Us – Matthew 1:23)
My name is Danielle Kriel, I'm 16 years old, I'm from South Africa, and this is my mum.
The problem that brought me here, to The SCOAN was:
I had cut myself since the age of 12 very badly, I attempted suicide numerous times,
and I was diagnosed with a lot of disorders -
bipolar disorder, border line personality disorder, and chronic depression.
It all started when I was about 6 years old.
I was sexually abused till the age of about 10, numerous times by numerous people.
Since the age of 8 I started biting and scratching and bruising - just lightly.
I wasn't sure what it did to me, it just made me feel better.
When I was 12 years old, I started cutting.
I was institutionalized for that and they told me that I would be in an institution for the rest of my life
and I would be on medications; that it was only manageable, not treatable.
Then, my suicidal attempts also started.
From then till now I have attempted suicides almost 120 - 150 times, and that's not even exaggerating.
We really fought it a lot and my parents couldn't really cope with this, so I was living with other families.
Every time my parents sent me away to other families, I would try not to mess up;
but then I would cut or attempt suicide, and they would send me back to my parents again.
When I messed up at my parents, they would send me back, so it was back and forth rejection the whole time.
The first time I attempted suicide - it was an overdose;
I overdosed on pills that I found in my mum's cupboard.
I have done it many times.
There were few near-death experiences as a result of that.
I have also taken poison and it made me sick but it didn't kill me.
I tried hanging myself.
At one point, when I was at my grandmother's house, I found a gun
and I thought that I could end it finally but then the grace of God stepped in:
As I held it in my hand, I just couldn't pull the trigger.
There were times when I would try to hit the vein, the artery to bleed out and to finally die.
When I was 12, I went on the internet and I literally typed it out on how to commit suicide.
It is surprising how many sites are there, encouraging people,
giving them methods how to commit suicide.
They encourage; they don't say, "Please, don't do it", they give structured methods how to do it -
step one, step two...
I've got a few ideas on that as well.
I've tried to electrocute myself.
I thought that if I could step in the bath with water, and I would cut a cable while it was plugged in and on,
and put it in the water, that it would electrocute me but it didn't work.
Recently, at the end of the last year, I was sleeping and then I woke up and I was in rage,
and I just thought to end it all - I grabbed the blade and I cut here, I hit the artery.
I cut it almost completely off.
I almost bled out.
The people I was staying with rushed me to the hospital; I was unconscious -
I couldn't really remember anything.
I remember; while I was there, I said, "I don't want to die".
I remember saying that when I felt that I was so close to death.
In the hospital, when I woke up and they got me stabilized,
the doctor told me that I had 30 millilitres of blood left inside of me.
He told me, "You have no idea how close to death you were".
It is physically impossible to even survive the drive from the house to the hospital on 30 ml of blood,
and I did, by the grace of God.
I didn't have brain damage or any other damage,
but by the time I got there, my organs started to fail and shut down,
but they didn't have any damage.
The first time I attempted it, I overdosed on pills because I thought that was the best way to do it,
and nothing happened, so I thought maybe I was doing it wrong.
I thought about going online; there must be a lot of people that have done it.
I just thought I could look for ideas there, and they gave me a lot of bad ideas.
It was really bad that they encouraged me.
I even asked there what the best, fastest and surest way to kill oneself was
if one has limited weapons or anything
because at that time, I was monitored by my mum, and I wouldn't have any weapons,
so I went to see what ordinary things I could use to kill myself.
I read that if you overdose on dettol, if you take a lot of it, it can kill you.
I have tried that but it also didn't work.
So you mean you physically drank dettol - the liquid - in an attempt to commit suicide?
Yes, they said that if you took enough of it, your lungs would swell up,
your heart would stop and you would die.
When I was 12, I started cutting.
From then till now, the cutting has gotten worse and worse.
At the beginning one cut would be enough to numb every emotion,
but the more I cut, the deeper I had to go.
I wanted to see the blood flow.
The craving was more to see the blood.
At the later stage, I started craving not to just see the blood, but also to drink the blood.
I started to crave that more and more.
The first thing that came was pain, an extreme emotional pain - it felt unbearable.
It came so suddenly.
After that thing, there was extreme rage.
Whether I wanted to do it or not, I still felt that I had to do it - I was like pushed into doing it.
It was like I would shut down and get everything ready and do it, regardless if I wanted it or not -
I just didn't have any control.
So, there was a force beyond your control, this urge that was pushing you to kill yourself and see blood?
Yes, it was.
I have tried to resist it on my own, but I just couldn't.
What about your dreams; can you describe to us the kind of attacks you were having spiritually in the nights?
Yes.
Since I was 8 years old, I had really bad nightmares.
I would dream about wild animals - tigers, wolfs attacking me,
I would dream of people abusing me in every kind of way.
I started to experience sleep paralysis; that was really horrifying to me.
I really didn't get a lot of sleep at all - it was really rare for me.
Either I would go to sleep and have a nightmare and when I woke up,
I didn't want to go back to sleep again because the dream would just continue,
or the whole night would be just a struggle to get the rage out that I was feeling,
and not to make any noise that somebody might come in and try to stop me.
The month before I came to The SCOAN, the attacks were getting worse and worse.
I would go for like a week without sleeping one night at all - just no sleep.
When I tried to sleep during the day, I would wake up and be in a rage.
Only in the month before I came here, I attempted suicide more than 15-20 times.
Even the night before I came here, I decided to end everything, that I mustn't come here,
I must die before I come here.
I don't know why but I was really scared.
We watched the movie "The Shack" about God's love, and I remember going to my room,
and I prayed to God and said, "God, I see Your love but I don't experience it".
Right then, they came into my room and told me, "You are flying to The SCOAN tomorrow".
I was so overwhelmed that I just gave the blades and the glass up.
Nothing really bad happened; because in the past, if I would give up blades,
I would experience hell, it would be a torture for more than a week -
I would really experience torture because I gave the blades up.
Wow, let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ.
We understand that the night before our sister came here to The SCOAN,
she actually was very close to committing suicide,
but to the glory of God, that was the night she was told she would be coming to the church,
and she submitted the blades that she had secretly found, with which she wanted to end her life,
and God brought her here today, to The SCOAN.
Sister, we saw in the clip earlier; as Prophet T.B. Joshua approached you, you were crying out,
and suddenly, as he began to pray, your hands began to shake and vibrate.
Could you just describe to us, for the glory of God, what happened to you at that moment,
as Prophet T.B. Joshua began to pray for you?
As he was standing in front of me, I held the photos, and he started shaking his hands,
and I just started shaking uncontrollably; I couldn't control it.
I can't really say what I felt - it was as if I was in kind of a fog.
Then he touched me on my head; it really hurt bad, and it felt like lightening or something had struck me.
So, all of that time you were not even conscious of yourself, when you were crying,
when that demon was manifesting, you just felt an electric shock hit you, as Prophet T.B. Joshua prayed?
Yes.
Have you ever experienced anything like that before?
No, never.
In the church I am now in South Africa - it is really a living church -
they have prayed for me a lot of times, but nothing would happen.
But now, to the glory of God; it has been one week since this encounter with Jesus Christ -
can you just testify to the world, what are the changes that you have seen in your life ever since then?
The changes are really incredible.
When he finally touched me, I felt lighter, I knew something left me, and I knew I was finally free.
My thoughts - they have really changed.
Normally my thoughts would be negative, disturbing and I didn't like it.
I would look at anything as a method to hurt myself, or to commit suicide;
anything could become a weapon.
Now, that is gone.
I can look at glass and knives and the thought wouldn't even come up.
As I looked on the tape, I saw the pictures of my open wounds, and normally that would satisfy me;
the deeper the wound, the more satisfaction,
but now, it really scared me to think that I really did that to myself.
In the past week, I really slept well - that's one thing that has changed completely.
I didn't have any nightmares in this whole week, which is really great,
because most of my life I had a nightmare or two every night.
I haven't experienced sleep paralysis even once.
I haven't had the urge to cut even once.
And the most important thing is: The pain of the past is over - it is over, and it doesn't hurt anymore.
Anything of the past is over - it is now just a testimony to glorify God.
Amen! Let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ!
So, since that encounter, the negative, suicidal thoughts have disappeared?
Yes.
I don't have any thought of hurting myself - everything is gone.
In the past week, my faith has grown so much.
I have experienced God's love for me.
Last week Sunday, Prophet T.B. Joshua said, "Heaven knows you are here".
This week I experienced it.
It was so overwhelming for me to realise
that Heaven, the Creator of everything, He is interested in this situation.
I looked back on what happened in the past, and I thought,
"Wow, the devil really tried to stop me, so there must be an awesome testimony, future and destiny
that he doesn't want me to step into".
Now, giving my testimony is the first step into my destiny.
Amen! Let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ!
All these are the scars that I...
Many of them have faded a lot, but these are no more to remind me of my past,
but rather they are a testimony to glorify Jesus.
My advice is: Anyone who is in my situation - do not give up hope, there is always hope.
There was a loving person who helped me; she paid for me to come here to The SCOAN.
She unconditionally loved me, like a mother, she was always there for me and supported me.
I know now, it was God loving me through her, God showing me His love through her.
Do not give up hope - by His stripes we are healed.
He has already shed every drop of blood for you.
You don't have to try to cover it with your own, because it is not going to work.
He already did everything for you.
People of God, the reason we are listening to this testimony and asking these questions
is to really encourage the world with what Jesus Christ is doing here.
The spirit that our sister was delivered from is the same spirit that we are seeing in operation around the world,
pushing people to join terrorist, militant groups that are involved in suicide bombing.
We read every day and see on the news what is happening.
This is the spirit that our sister was delivered from; a spirit that would push her to kill herself,
and even if she couldn't kill herself, that same spirit would eventually push her
to also end the lives of others.
As you heard her say earlier, the spirit was actually pushing her just to see blood,
and she tried to isolate herself because she felt if she was in the public,
she would even injure or maim others as well.
We can imagine the spirit that we are talking about, that our sister was delivered from.
That spirit is what is pushing people to travel overseas to join terrorist groups,
to actually end their own lives and kill innocent people, just to try to satisfy that evil spirit.
We give glory to God that our sister was delivered.
If not for this deliverance, who knows what would have happened.
Perhaps she would not only have ended her life,
but that spirit would have pushed her to also injure and affect others as well.
The light of God that exposed that spirit and sent the darkness packing in her,
that is the light of God that is present here, in the arena of liberty.
It is time for us to celebrate that light.
Let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ.
Yes; when the light of God speaks, darkness has no hiding place.
We can see clearly that our sister is completely delivered from that wicked, tormenting spirit,
that wanted at all costs for her to end her life, to see blood, to kill herself and others.
Today, she is free, and that same power of God that set her free
is available for those who are ready and open to receive.
Emmanuel!
(God With Us – Matthew 1:23)
I'm Mara Kriel and I'm the mother of Danielle Kriel.
During this week, after the deliverance of Danielle, she sleeps completely through the night,
she doesn't have nightmares anymore, and the other thing is: She is very optimistic and enthusiastic.
She is talking a lot; in the past she didn't talk much to me, she avoided me, she was quiet.
She is completely changed - 180 degrees from what she was and what she now is.
Glory to God, and to the man of God, and to the people who support and sponsored us to come here.
All glory to God for His mercy and His grace.
Amen, let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ.
Madam, as her mother, could you just compare her life before she came here to the differences now -
just give us a quick example of her life before and to the changes you have seen since that deliverance.
When she was still sick, I was watching her 24/7, and it took a toll on me.
She was not focusing, she was acting like a zombie, so to speak.
This even had an influence on my work.
I feel rest, complete peace now that she is here and she has been delivered.
She sleeps during the night and she is fine.
I'm very grateful.
Amen, let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ.
Don't despair, God is there for everybody.
Jesus Christ gave His blood for us and we are created in the image of God.
Through the blood of Jesus Christ we can be saved, if we allow Him, if we act upon His Word,
and if we obey Him, there is hope for us; there is salvation.
There is joy, peace - only God can give peace.
Hallelujah, let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ one more time.
Thank You, Jesus - I'm completely free!
STANDARD FOR LIFE
My name is Danielle Kriel and I'm from South Africa.
Three weeks ago I was delivered from the spirit of suicide.
My life has completely changed around; I couldn't sleep, now I sleep like a baby throughout the night,
I don't have any more nightmares, no more depressive thoughts, everything is positive,
I'm getting happy again and I'm thinking about my future - something that I normally didn't do.
I've been so blessed in these 3 weeks - it has been a really awesome experience.
My faith has grown so much.
I've learnt so much through the lectures every Sunday service - it has been really amazing.
I'm feeling awesome; I'm very strong.
My spiritual life has really grown - I feel confident in my relationship in Jesus Christ.
These 3 weeks changed my life.
I'm really going back a wholly different person than the person that came here.
No more thoughts of suicide, depression, of hurting myself or others.
No more negative thoughts; everything is positive; thinking about the future,
praying a lot and engaging with God - my relationship has grown stronger.
With my mum, the reconciliation also happened; and the relationship with God.
Even to come here, we couldn't afford to come here - someone had to sponsor us to come here,
where I stayed for 3 months - this person said she was going to pay for us coming here.
Our sister is fully equipped to go back to her home, to her country,
and maintain the deliverance, and to make the Word of God the standard for her life.
Sister, right now, we actually have a wonderful message for you from Prophet T.B. Joshua.
The man of God, Prophet T.B. Joshua said on behalf of himself and Emmanuel TV partners around the world,
he really wants to support you, as you start your new life in Christ Jesus,
returning back to your country - South Africa.
Especially in the area of your academic life, and to provide for you and your mum,
Prophet T.B. Joshua said he is here to present to you the gift of $2000.
Thank You, Jesus!
We needed this.
We didn't expect this coming here, we just expected deliverance.
We have been blessed so much, spiritually and financially.
We have been blessed with the faith tools - thank you, man of God.
Thank You, Jesus.
Do not give up hope; no matter how dark things seem.
God will use one of His servants, someone that is willing to listen to Him,
to shine His light and His love in your darkness.
I have experienced it.
It seemed that there was no hope - this was my last bus stop,
and I said, "If this doesn't work, then nothing is going to work".
There is always hope - never lose hope; hope in Christ Jesus.
I'm Mara Kriel, I'm from South Africa.
She is delivered completely.
She is so happy, enthusiastic.
She is now talking about the future; things which she didn't do in the past.
I'm very grateful.
Thank God, for His mercy and His grace.
The man of God, Prophet T.B. Joshua - to give us this gift on his birthday - we are very grateful.
And I thank God for my daughter - I've got my daughter back - she is talented.
May she just expand in her spiritual life and wisdom.
Really, I'm overwhelmed, because I've got so many financial constraints.
When I'm going back, there are a lot of things to pay and this money will come in very handy.
Just for Danielle - for her education, I will not worry for that part anymore.
That's wonderful - thank you, man of God.
Never despair, God is there.
Even if your life is in a dark pit, never give up hope, because God is light, He is Spirit, He is Love.
We are created in the image of God.
If He is interested in making a small snowflake, with such detail - just for a while, and then it fades away,
it melts - how much more does He care about me and you.
We are in His image.
What can I say?
Thank God.
Thank You, Jesus!
TT ROBERT BEGIER 18/09/2018
RV: Mel Flowers 28/09/2018